# Ian Pekunsal

♥ Toronto, Canada 🝙 ian@pknsl.com 🔲 (647) 847-8487 🔚 in/ugurpekunsal 👝 https://pknsl.com

#### SUMMARY

Web developer with expertise in front-end development and an in-depth understanding of back-end development practices and methodologies, thus able to work on both ends of a project to assist the team, balance the workload, and meet project deadlines.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Web Developer

**Sylogist** 

May 2022 - July 2023, Barrie, ON

- · Integrated Microsoft Dynamics CRMs with CMS systems.
- · Developed the front end according to wireframes and user stories.
- · Applied performance fixes to reduce loading times and decrease Azure operating costs.

# Freelance Web Developer

Destinade

June 2020 - May 2022, North York, ON

- · Developed and maintained travel management software.
- · Implemented new features, tested, and debugged the software.
- $\cdot \ \ Gained\ valuable\ experience\ in\ software\ development,\ project\ management,\ and\ customer\ service.$

# Junior Web Developer

**Gri Creative** 

June 2018 - May 2020, Kadikoy, Istanbul

- $\cdot$  Applied custom layouts to existing portals and fixed bugs.
- · Collaborated closely with senior developers to understand requirements and design specifications.
- · Used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript skills to create visually appealing and functional layouts.
- · Participated in code reviews with colleagues to ensure the quality and consistency of the codebase.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Software Engineering Technician Honor's Diploma

Centennial College • Scarborough, ON • 2022 • 3.48

· CCSAI Excellence in Academics and Leadership Scholarship

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### AZ-900

learn.microsoft.com • 2023

# INVOLVEMENT

#### **Volunteer Event Technician**

Ottawa, ON · Federation for the Humanities and Social Sciences · June 2022

- · Assisted presenters with equipment setup and conducting test runs.
- Throughout the presentations, I intervened if either the presenter or a significant portion of the audience faced technical issues.
- $\cdot \ \text{Maintained attendance records and reported the specifics of any technical issues encountered.}$

#### **SKILLS**

# Technical Skills:

UI/UX, SEO, OOP, Agile, SCRUM, Responsive Design.

# Front End Development:

ReactJS 2 years - SASS/CSS/HTML 3 years - jQuery 3 years - Bootstrap 3 years

## **Back End Development:**

Node.js 2 years - SQL 1 year - MySQL 3 years - MongoDB 2 years

Project Management, Time Management, Communication, Problem-Solving, Critical Thinking, Analytics, Creativity, and Eagerness to Learn.